HARSH GUPTA

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Profile Info

Resourceful professional in building scalable and reliable backend API services and integrate them with user friendly components to serve vast volume of client traffic while ensuring best user experience. Have worked in a variety of areas that includes creating and deploying REST APIs with Django Rest Framework and Nestjs, crawling. Have also worked on React.js and Next.js apps

Contact

Location New Delhi

Phone +91-9999537290

Email hg070401@gmail.com

Profiles

- LeetCode 1700 + rating
- Linkedin
- My Website

Tech Stack

Languages

- Python
- JavaScript
- Typescript

Framework/Libraries/Technologies

- Django/ Django Rest FrameWork
- Nest js
- Prisma
- React.js
- NEXT.js
- GIT

Databases

- MySQL
- FireStore
- MongoDB

Experience

Software Engineering Intern-Backend

Feb 2023-

Adani Digital Labs

Present

- Developed APIs using Nest.js and utilized Prisma ORM for the customer care executive dashboard's backend.
- Implemented TypeScript utilities across all DTOs to optimize the code
- Refactored the codebase to enhance performance, improve maintainability and reduce cognitive complexity

Software Engineering Intern-Full Satck

JUNE 2022-AUG 2022

GetWork

- Single-handedly built a user onboarding flow from conceptualisation till
- Implemented encrypted token-based authentication system, where the session is maintained accross subdomain using cookie and localstorage management.
- Working collaboratively with CTO in improving GetWork's products by adding and optimising features.
- Integration of user-facing elements developed by user-interface developers with server-side logic

Software Engineering Intern-Backend

AUG 2021 -OCT 2021

GetWork

- Made and maintained many APIs using Django-rest-framework.
- Contributed to making a real-time chat feature using React.js and Firebase.
- Used web Scraping for providing insightful leads to the sales team.
- · Reusable code and libraries were created for future usage, and the programme was optimised for optimal performance and scalability

Projects

<u>Customer Relationship Management System</u>

- This is a costumer relationship management system where an organization can register and then create agents under them.
- Leads will be created by organiser and assign them to respective agents.
- This was created using django and using django templates as frontend.

Education

Bachelor of Technology

2019-2023

Information Technology

Maharaja Agrasen Institute of Technology Guru Gobind Singh Indraprastha University, New Delhi, India